

- Sydney, Australia (Citizenship: Canadian)
- Australian Work Rights: Subclass 186 Visa
- mathew.w.mclean@gmail.com
- mwmclean.github.io
- m www.linkedin.com/in/mathew-mclean-96082783
- +61 452 389 372

Experienced data scientist and Scrum Master with a PhD in Operations Research and expertise in statistical computing, machine learning, and software development. Published researcher in advanced regression and time -series models, Bayesian methods, and biostatistics.

EDUCATION

Ph.D. in Operations Research

Dissertation: On Generalized Additive Models for Regression with Functional Data

Cornell University - Ithaca, NY, USA •

2008 - 2013 🗯

B.Sc. (Hons.) in Statistics

University of Manitoba

Winnipeg, MB, CAN •

2004 - 2008 🗯

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Data Scientist - Displayr

Designed features for BI and market research software, contributing to the company's growth from 20 to 100+ employees and nearly \$14 million in ARR

2021 - 2024 🗯

Data Science Team Lead - Displayr

Lead a team of data scientists to write fast, easy-to-use tools for text analysis, machine learning, regression, and choice modeling using Scrum.

2019 - 2021 🗯

Computational Statistician - Displayr

Maintained/co-authored a suite of $40+\ R$ packages for statistical modeling, visualization, data cleaning and integrating with various web APIs.

2017 - 2019 茸

SKILLS

Programming

o R o Python o JavaScript o SQL o stan o git

Other tools

Agile Methodologies
Circle CI
docker
Snowflake
Reproducible Research
JIRA

CERTIFICATIONS

- SAFe® Practice Consultant (SPC)
- 🕒 SAFe® Release Train Engineer (RTE)
- Professional Scrum Master II (PSMII)
- 🕒 Pro. Agile Leadership Evidence Based Management
- Professional Scrum Product Owner I (PSPOI)
- Professional Scrum Facilitation Skills (PSF)

SAMPLE PROJECTS

Automatic categorization of open-ended text

ML and AI models (ChatGPT) to classify survey responses without text coding

Displayr - Semi-Automatic Text Categorization

RefManageR

Tools for finding, importing, formatting, searching, and printing bibliographic references in R.

- CRAN RefManageR
- github.com/ropensci/refmanager

SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

Variational Message Passing for Elaborate Response Regression Models

- M. W. McLean and M. P. Wand
- Bayesian Analysis (2019)
- ODI: 10.1214/18-BA1098

Functional Generalised Additive Models

- M. W. McLean, G. Hooker, et al.
- Journal of Computational and Graphical Statistics (2014)
- **O** DOI: 10.1080/10618600.2012.729985

Forecasting Emergency Medical Service Call Arrivals

- D. S. Matteson, M. W. McLean, et al.
- Annals of Applied Statistics (2011)
- **9** DOI: 10.1214/10-AOAS442